{"tossups": [{"question": "An economic effect named for this author arose from his description of a spiraling pattern ofconsumption in his essay \"Regrets on Parting with my Old Dressing Gown\". One of his works endsby noting \"He who laughs last, laughs best\"; that work's narrator meets the title character in theRegency Cafe, where they discuss the War of the Buffoons and the Enlightenment. This man stoleplot elements from Tristram Shandy for a work whose protagonist believes that all (*) events are\"written up above\" in a \"great scroll\". This author of Rameau's Nephew and Jacques the Fatalist workedwith Jean d'Alembert to produce a \"Systematic Dictionary of the Sciences, Arts, and Crafts\". For 10 points,name this chief editor of the Encyclopedie.", "answer": "Denis Diderot", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "Denis <b><u>Diderot</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Denis Diderot", "Diderot"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This character inadvertently starts a fight with a girl nicknamed \"The Queen of Spades\" while walking back from a dance. This character runs away from a fancy hotel called \"The Herons\" in Sandbourne and earlier accidentally drives the family horse Prince into a fatal collision with the mailman's cart. A troop of policemen find her sleeping on an altar in (*) Stonehenge, and the novel ends with her husband looking at the black flag signaling her death with her sister Liza-Lu. She befriends Retty Priddle and Izz Huett while working at Talbothay's Dairy Farm, where she meets her husband, who flees to Brazil after learning that she had been raped by Alec. For 10 points, name this \"pure woman\" who marries Angel Clare in the Thomas Hardy novel named for her.", "answer": "Tess Durbeyfield [or Tess d'Urberville; or Tess of the d'Urbervilles; prompt on \"Durbeyfield\" or \"d'Urberville\"]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Tess Durbeyfield</u></b> [or <b><u>Tess d'Urberville</u></b>; or <b><u>Tess of the d'Urbervilles</u></b>; prompt on <u>Durbeyfield</u> or <u>d'Urberville</u>]", "acceptable": ["Tess Durbeyfield", "Tess Durbeyfield", "Tess d'Urberville", "Tess of the d'Urbervilles"], "promptable": ["Durbeyfield", "d'Urberville"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One author from this country wrote a novel in which the orphans Esteban and Sofia encounter the French revolutionary Victor Hugues and a novel set on Lenormand de Mezy's plantation that stars the slaves Mackandal and Ti Noel. That author from this country wrote Explosion in aCathedral and developed the theory of lo real marvailloso, a forerunner to magical realism, in the prologue to The Kingdom of this World. Another author from this country described his verse as \"a wounded deer seeking refuge on the mountain\" and wrote \"Cultivo Una Rosa Blanca\", which appears in (*) Versos Sencillos and was adapted into the patriotic song \"Guantanamera\". Alejo Carpentier and Jose Marti were from, for 10 points, which Caribbean island nation?", "answer": "Republic of Cuba [or Republica de Cuba; accept Switzerland or the Swiss Confederation until \"wounded deer\" is read, since Carpentier was born in Switzerland but identified as Cuban]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Republic of <b><u>Cuba</u></b> [or <b><u>Republica de Cuba</u></b>; accept <b><u>Switzerland</u></b> or the <b><u>Swiss Confederation until \"wounded deer\" is read,</u></b> since Carpentier was born in Switzerland but identified as Cuban]", "acceptable": ["Republic of Cuba", "Cuba", "Republica de Cuba", "Switzerland", "Swiss Confederation until \"wounded deer\" is read,"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The law governing this phenomenon in one regime has a coefficient equal to C divided by thequantity T minus theta, where theta accounts for the exchange interaction. Gadolinium-containingMRI contrast agents show the \"super\" version of this phenomenon. It is displayed by all high-spincoordination complexes. This phenomenon arises in materials with positive susceptibility. Thisphenomenon, which is described by the linear Curie-Weiss law, arises in systems with (*) unpairedelectrons and in ferromagnets above the Curie temperature. It arises when dipoles align in the samedirection as an applied field. For 10 points, name this property of some materials in which they are attractedby external magnetic fields, often contrasted with diamagnetism.", "answer": "paramagnetism [or word forms, like paramagnetic or paramagnets]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>paramagnetism</u></b> [or <b><u>word forms, like paramagnetic</u></b> or <b><u>paramagnets</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["paramagnetism", "paramagnetism", "word forms, like paramagnetic", "paramagnets"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This artist's early work includes a book of drawings from the Bronx and Central Park Zoos titledAnimal Sketching. He did the set design for Erik Satie's Socrate and created the work 125 for JFKAirport. He constructed figures made out of cloth, buttons and wire for an installation in theWhitney Museum titled (*) Circus. The name for his most iconic creations was coined by MarcelDuchamp. One of his works is installed in front of the Federal Center Plaza in Chicago and evokes theimage of a giant bird. This man created a 76-foot-long work for the ceiling of the East Building at theNational Gallery of Art. For 10 points, name this artist of Flamingo and Lobster Trap and Fish Tail, bestknown for his mobiles.", "answer": "Alexander Calder", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Alexander <b><u>Calder</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Alexander Calder", "Calder"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "German linguist Theodor Noldeke wrote a popular \"introductory history\" of this book. Though itis not the Kebra Nagast, this book describes a campaign in the Year of the Elephant led by theChristian zealot Abraha. This book holds that mankind was created from a single clot of blood. Anoft-memorized passage about a (*) chair that symbolizes God's rule over mankind is found in the secondand longest section of this book. Three pagan goddesses are praised in a controversial section of this bookknown as the Satanic Verses. Sections named Yasin and Fatiha are found in this book, which praises thePeople of the Book. Compiled into book form by Abu Bakr and divided into suras, for 10 points, name thisholy book verbally revealed by Gabriel to the prophet Muhammad.", "answer": "Qu'ran [or Koran]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Qu'ran</u></b> [or <b><u>Koran</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Qu'ran", "Qu'ran", "Koran"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One ruler of this dynasty expanded the Academy of Gondishapur. Another ruler was known as\"the Sinner\" after persecuting Christians. Another ruler of this dynasty ascended to power in uterovia the crown placed on his mother's belly. This dynasty's final ruler was defeated at the \"Victory ofVictories\", the Battle of Nahavand, by the forces of the Rashidun Caliphate. Another ruler of thisdynasty, (*) Khosrau II, fought a series of battles against Heraclius' Byzantine forces. After besiegingEdessa, another ruler of this empire captured the Roman emperor Valerian. Its first ruler was Ardashir. For10 points, name this Persian dynasty of Shapur I which ruled from Ctesiphon.", "answer": "Sassanid dynasty/empire [or Sassanians; prompt on \"Persian\" Empire; prompt on \"Iran\"ian Empire]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Sassanid dynasty/empire</u></b> [or <b><u>Sassanians</u></b>; prompt on <u>Persian\" Empire</u>; prompt on <u>Iran\"ian Empire</u>]", "acceptable": ["Sassanid dynasty/empire", "Sassanid dynasty/empire", "Sassanians"], "promptable": ["Persian\" Empire", "Iran\"ian Empire"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This process is basically complete in subjects that pass the \"wug test\" without thinking. Thisprocess results from the setting of parameters according to the principles and parameters approach,and its progression includes the \"telegraphic stage\". A girl named Genie served as evidence for thecritical period hypothesis of this process. In response to Skinner, a believer in an organic \"device\"for this process gave the (*) \"poverty of the stimulus\" argument, which implies that behaviorism couldn'texplain its rapidity. That argument came from Noam Chomsky, who believed it was aided by a universalgrammar. For 10 points, name this process which occurs without teaching in the minds of young children,allowing them to comprehend and utter sentences.", "answer": "first language acquisition [or language learning, \"learning a language,\" etc.; prompt on \"learning to talk\" or \"learning grammar\"; accept learning to pluralize or learning to pronounce before \"parameters\"]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>first language acquisition</u></b> [or <b><u>language learning, \"learning a language,\" etc.</u></b>; prompt on <u>learning to talk</u> or <u>learning grammar</u>; accept <b><u>learning to pluralize</u></b> or <b><u>learning to pronounce</u></b> before \"parameters]", "acceptable": ["first language acquisition", "first language acquisition", "language learning, \"learning a language,\" etc.", "learning to pluralize", "learning to pronounce"], "promptable": ["learning to talk", "learning grammar"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This protein forms aggregates in Hirano bodies. This protein is imaged using fluorescentphalloidin, and in red blood cells it complexes with band 4.1 protein at the ends of spectrin. It bindsto catenins on the cytoplasmic side of adherens junctions. Upon binding to ATP, it switches from aglobular form to a more aggregation-prone form, which creates a helical string. This protein isresponsible for forming the mechanism that pinches cells apart in (*) cytokinesis, and it is alsoresponsible for extending pseudopods in amoebas. Polymers of this protein move closer together duringmuscle contraction, due to myosin attaching to this protein and pulling. For 10 points, name this proteinthat forms the thin filaments of the cytoskeleton.", "answer": "actin [or thin filaments before mention; prompt on \"filaments\" before mention]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>actin</u></b> [or <b><u>thin filaments</u></b> before mention; prompt on <u>filaments\"</u> before mention]", "acceptable": ["actin", "actin", "thin filaments"], "promptable": ["filaments\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The author of this document had earlier stated his potential opposition to it in an open letter toHorace Greeley. Horatio Seymour declared it \"a proposal for the butchery of women and children\".A predecessor to this document, regarding \"contrabands,\" was issued by Benjamin Butler and madeofficial policy in the First (*) Confiscation Act. Its final version did not contain the colonization proposalspresent in the preliminary draft. It was issued following a victory for George McClellan over Robert E. Leeat the Battle of Antietam and was expanded to include the entire country by the Thirteenth Amendment.For 10 points, name this document that, in states engaged in open rebellion against the United States, freedthe slaves.", "answer": "The Emancipation Proclamation ", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Emancipation Proclamation</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Emancipation Proclamation", "Emancipation Proclamation"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This composer wrote a series of sonatas for nearly every instrument of the orchestra, most ofwhich he could play, as well as a Symphony in B-flat for wind ensemble. He composed a suite for violaand orchestra for the English king George V, his Trauermusik. That piece is an example of his musicfor a purpose, or Gebrauchsmusik. He also created a choral piece setting Whitman's poem (*) \"WhenLilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom'd,\" composed a series of Symphonic Metamorphoses on themes of CarlMaria von Weber, and wrote an opera based on the life of Matthias Grunewald. For 10 points, name thisearly to mid-20th century German composer of Mathis der Mahler.", "answer": "Paul Hindemith", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Paul Hindemith</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Paul Hindemith", "Paul Hindemith"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "During a festival for this god, an arrow was fired at an edible likeness of him and those youngmen who ate his body had to serve him for one year. In that festival, a priest who impersonated hislieutenant Paynal ran and led a procession. After the consecration of this god's Great Temple, a rackwas erected to display the heads of 20,000 humans sacrificed to him. He was often depicted with ablue and black face. This god slew the 400 stars, led by his sister (*) Coyolxauhqui(co-yol-SHAW-chee), after they tormented his mother for becoming impregnated by a ball of feathers. Thisson of Coatlicue was guided by an eagle perched upon a cactus to lead his people to their new home. For 10points, name this \"left-handed hummingbird,\" an Aztec war and sun god.", "answer": "Huitzilopochtli [or left-handed hummingbird before mention]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Huitzilopochtli</u></b> [or <b><u>left-handed hummingbird</u></b> before mention]", "acceptable": ["Huitzilopochtli", "Huitzilopochtli", "left-handed hummingbird"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One area in this city is linked by its Necklace District to its Grand Circus Park Historic District,while its building projects include a River Walk near the Renaissance Center. It's not Cleveland, butQuicken Loans moved its headquarters here in 2010. Its current mayor defeated Ken Cockrel in aspecial election after his predecessor, who had hosted a party at the Manoogian Mansion, went to (*)jail. In April 2012, this city's current mayor checked into a hospital twice during negotiations with RickSnyder over whether the governor's office could appoint a state financial manager to sell art in the citymuseum to pay debts. Kwame Kilpatrick and Dave Bing have both been mayors of, for 10 points, what cityknown as the center of the U.S. automotive industry?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "Current Events", "subcategory": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Detroit</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Detroit", "Detroit"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "He's not Henry VIII, but this man did greatly upset Hugh de Lusignan by claiming he didn'treceive a papal dispensation to marry his first wife so that he could subsequently marry Isabella ofAngouleme. He won a victory over rival claimant Arthur of Brittany at the Battle of Mirebeau.Following a later battle, this monarch agreed to a treaty whose Clause 61 he subsequently disobeyed,sparking the First (*) Barons' War. He participated in an unsuccessful rebellion while his brother, theking, was on the Third Crusade. This loser of the Battle of Bouvines was the youngest son of Henry II andwas known early in his life by the epithet \"Lackland\". For 10 points, name this English monarch who wasforced to sign the Magna Carta.", "answer": "King John I [or John Lackland]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>King John I</u></b> [or <b><u>John Lackland</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["King John I", "King John I", "John Lackland"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one work, this man used an extended simile likening the Catholic hierarchy to broods of fairies.He began his magnum opus with twelve chapters of axiomatic definitions, and later in that workcriticized the misinterpretation of Scripture by a \"confederacy of deceivers.\" This thinker believedmen are equally able to use body and mind to kill one another, and that competition, diffidence, andglory produce a \"war of (*) all against all.\" He argued that absent a failure to protect against externalinvasion, nothing can break the covenant of absolute duty to the sovereign. For 10 points, name this tutor ofCharles II, who was inspired by the English Civil War to write that the state of nature is \"solitary, poor,nasty, brutish, and short\" in Leviathan.", "answer": "Thomas Hobbes", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Thomas Hobbes</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Thomas Hobbes", "Thomas Hobbes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author mused \"I have walked into Perigord, I have seen the torch-flames, high-leaping\" in apoem about Narbonne, Excideuil and Rochecoart, \"Provincia Deserta\". Bertrans de Born cries\"May God damn for ever all who cry 'Peace!'\" in another poem by this author, who wrote of a manwho seeks to \"resuscitate the dead art of poetry\" in his (*) Hugh Selwyn Mauberley. This author of\"Sestina: Altaforte\" described \"the apparition of these faces in the crowd\" as \"petals on a wet, black bough\"in \"In a Station of the Metro\". Sections like \"Rock Drill\" make up his longest poetic work, which usesChinese characters and expresses approval of fascism in its \"Italian\" and \"Pisan\" sections. For 10 points,name this Imagist poet of The Cantos.", "answer": "Ezra Weston Loomis Pound", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Ezra Weston Loomis <b><u>Pound</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ezra Weston Loomis Pound", "Pound"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Fossils from this period come from the laggerstatten of Sirius Passet and Chengjiang, and theTreptichnus pedum assemblage of trace fossils is used to define its base. The breakup of Pannotiabegan at its start. Archeocyathids are index fossils for this period, which features the first knowncrustacean fossils. Many of the most important fossils from this period were found in the (*) Burgessshale. This period is the first of the Paleozoic and is followed by the Ordovician. Trilobites make theirdebut in the fossils of this period. The time period before it is simply dubbed \"pre-\" this, and it featured alarge boom in diversity of Earth's fauna, its namesake explosion. For 10 points, name this geologic periodnamed for the Latin name of Wales.", "answer": "Cambrian period", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Cambrian</u></b> period", "acceptable": ["Cambrian period", "Cambrian"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A demon flies towards a hanged woman in Despair, a scene in this artist's series on the seven vices. The enthroned St. Peter of his Stefaneschi Triptych is drawn similarly to Mary in his Ognissanti Madonna. The blue ceiling of his most famous work is decorated with stars and circular busts of Jesus and the Four Apostles. Christ extends his arms and is surrounded by a rainbow in his Last Judgment. He designed a tall bell tower in Florence. Angels fly recklessly above a craggy rock in the(*) Lamentation scene by this student of Cimabue; that scene was commissioned to atone for the sins of the usurer, Enrico Scrovegni. For 10 points, name this artist of the early Italian Renaissance who created the Arena Chapel frescoes.", "answer": "Giotto di Bondone", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Giotto di <b><u>Bondone</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Giotto di Bondone", "Bondone"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The applied strength of this technique is measured in RCFs, and tabletop versions of theseinstruments usually have a \"Fast Temp\" option. Polyribosome binding to mRNA is commonlymeasured using the isopycnic version of this technique. Using a sucrose gradient with this techniqueallows sedimentation velocity analysis, and in that case the coefficients are measured in Svedbergunits. Cell fractionation uses this technique to extract (*) organelles, and this technique typically formsa pellet with a supernatant on top. It can also be used to remove blood plasma from formed elements. For10 points, name this technique whose power is measured in units of g, which is used to separate mixturesby spinning them around really quickly.", "answer": "centrifugation [or word forms of centrifuge]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>centrifugation</u></b> [or <b><u>word forms of centrifuge</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["centrifugation", "centrifugation", "word forms of centrifuge"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "During this event, the U.S. created EXCOMM, which included Llewellyn Thompson andMcGeorge Bundy. It was partially triggered by the Project Emily deal with the UK. Rudolf Andersenwas a casualty of this event. Depth charges were dropped on the B-59 during it, leading to a scramblefrom Wrangel Island. The agreement that ended this event was negotiated by U Thant and wasnamed for the (*) Hotline that it created. It was resolved by agreeing to remove the Turkish Jupiters. Thisincident was triggered by a Richard-Heyser-piloted U-2 taking pictures of several bases under constructionnear San Cristobal. 14 ships were turned back by a quarantine during, for 10 points, what Cold Warincident, which ended with Khrushchev agreeing to remove the namesake weapons?", "answer": "Cuban Missile Crisis [or the Caribbean Crisis; prompt on \"October Crisis\" to distinguish it from the Canadian thing]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Cuban Missile Crisis</u></b> [or the <b><u>Caribbean Crisis</u></b>; prompt on <u>October Crisis\" to distinguish it from the Canadian thing</u>]", "acceptable": ["Cuban Missile Crisis", "Cuban Missile Crisis", "Caribbean Crisis"], "promptable": ["October Crisis\" to distinguish it from the Canadian thing"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Tumors that secrete this hormone are treated with streptozocin. GLP-1 triggers its release, andanalogues of it include NPH and Detemir. Six molecules of this hormone are coordinated to zinc in avesicle. It leads to increased GLUT transporter activity in target tissues through tyrosine kinaseactivation. By activating PP2A, this molecule inhibits triglyceride breakdown, and in the liver itstimulates glycogen formation. One common disease sees peripheral tissues become (*) resistant to thishormone, which is secreted from the beta cells of the islets of Langerhans. This hormone's action opposesthat of glucagon and serves to decrease blood glucose. For 10 points, name this hormone secreted from thepancreas, whose levels are insufficient in diabetes.", "answer": "insulin", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>insulin</u></b>", "acceptable": ["insulin", "insulin"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "These events were authorized by Innocent VIII's papal bull Summis desiderantes affectibus.Reginald Scot's criticism of these events led to his works being burned by James I. One of them tookplace in North Berwick, Scotland in 1590, thirty-six years before the W\u00c3\u00bcrzburg one. Gottfried Voigtclaimed that nine million people were (*) victims of these events in Europe, which began in thefourteenth century and declined in the eighteenth century. Heinrich Kramer wrote a handbook to be usedduring these events, the Malleus Maleficarum. Another of these events was triggered by the slave Titubabeing accused by Abigail Williams and was supported by Cotton Mather. For 10 points, name these events,one of which occurred in Salem in 1692.", "answer": "witch trials [or witch hunts; accept logical equivalents]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>witch trials</u></b> [or <b><u>witch hunts</u></b>; accept <b><u>logical equivalents</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["witch trials", "witch trials", "witch hunts", "logical equivalents"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Around his neck, this character wears a silver dollar and a lock of hair which is later seized andthrown into a fire. He helps carry a basket of hot bread rolls for a drunk woman named Prue whotells him about how her child died when her milk dried up. Despite his trouble writing the letter G,he succeeds in writing a letter to his wife Chloe. This character, who was inspired by (*) JosiahHenson, has a vision of Jesus that inspires him to refuse to divulge information about Cassy and Emmeline.While traveling on a steamboat, he jumps overboard and saves the drowning Eva St. Clare. George Shelbyarrives too late to save this character, who is flogged to death by Simon Legree's overseers. For 10 points,name this title slave of a Harriet Beecher Stowe novel.", "answer": "Uncle Tom", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Uncle Tom</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Uncle Tom", "Uncle Tom"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One structure in this city features a sculpture in which bearded warriors look up at a wingedwoman who shouts and points a sword; that sculpture is called Departure of the Volunteers. A theaterin this city depicts Poetry and Harmony in gilded angelic statues on its front face, and is home to abifurcating Grand Staircase as well as a bronze chandelier insisted on by Charles Garnier, whodesigned that namesake (*) opera house of this city. Many famous people are buried in this non-Romecity's Pantheon building in its Latin Quarter. This city also features an I.M. Pei-designed glass pyramid infront of its art museum. For 10 points, name this city where the Champs-Elys\u00c3\u00a9es passes under the Arc deTriomphe, the home of the Louvre and the Eiffel Tower.", "answer": "Paris", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Paris</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Paris", "Paris"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "Answer some questions about the Diophantine equation a x plus b y equals c, for 10 points each:", "answers": ["INTEGERS", "GCF", "PELL"], "parts": ["] Since the equation is Diophantine, it only accepts these values as inputs. This set of numbers, symbolized with a blackboard Z, includes both positive and negative whole numbers.", "The value of c in that equation must divide this function of a and b. This value, which can be computed from the Euclidean algorithm, is the largest integer that divides both a and b.", "This other Diophantine equation is named for a British mathematician and is written x squared minus n times y squared equals 1. It is often solved using continued fractions."], "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>INTEGERS</u></b>", "<b><u>GCF</u></b>", "<b><u>PELL</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["INTEGERS", "INTEGERS"], ["GCF", "GCF"], ["PELL", "PELL"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}, {"leadin": "This body's officials served a term of two months before being replaced by officials from other families. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["SIGNORIA", "FLORENCE", "LORENZO"], "parts": ["Identify this legislative body, which included such positions as the Gonfaloniere of Justice, and expanded in size after the fall of the Albizzi.", "The Signoria was the legislative body of this city-state, the site of the Ciompi Revolt and the Pazzi Conspiracy", "The leader targeted in the Pazzi Conspiracy was this member of the Medici family who created the Council of Twelve Good Men and was eclipsed as Florentine leader by Savonarola upon his death."], "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answers_formatted": ["<b><u>SIGNORIA</u></b>", "<b><u>FLORENCE</u></b>", "<b><u>LORENZO</u></b>"], "acceptable": [["SIGNORIA", "SIGNORIA"], ["FLORENCE", "FLORENCE"], ["LORENZO", "LORENZO"]], "promptable": [[], [], []], "rejectable": [[], [], []], "metadata": ["", "", ""]}]}